Curriculum Vitae

Ryunosuke "Ryan" Goto, M.D.

Resident Physician, Department of Pediatrics at the University of Tokyo Hospital Email: rgoto@m.u-tokyo.ac.jp



I am a Pediatrics Resident at the University of Tokyo Hospital and Nagano Children's Hospital. After receiving primary and secondary education in the United Kingdom and the United States, I received my M.D. from the University of Tokyo in 2019. My research interests are adverse childhood experiences (war in particular) and their relationship with development, mental health, and chronic disease, as well as the genome-environment interaction that shapes a child's health and development. I am also interested in evaluating social and economic determinants of and inequities in the health of children and adolescents. My work has been published in *The* Lancet, JAMA Pediatrics, and Pediatrics, among other journals.

M.D., Faculty of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan **Education**

04/2013 - 03/2019

Monta Vista High School, Cupertino, CA, USA

08/2008 - 06/2012

Work Experience

Nagano Children's Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics

10/2021 -

The University of Tokyo Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics 04/2019 - 09/2021

IBM Research

Research Intern 02/2019 - 03/2019

Explored possible applications of automated connected speech analysis in the detection of pragmatic language impairment in individuals with autistic spectrum disorder

United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East Intern

07/2017 - 09/2017

Quality improvement and research on the dissemination and implementation of an electronic maternal and child health handbook application, e-MCH Handbook For more information on the e-MCH Handbook:

http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631 02.pdf

Publications

Peer-reviewed publications

Ryunosuke Goto, Yusuke Okubo, Norbert Skokauskas. Reasons and trends in youth's suicide rates during the COVID-19 pandemic. *The Lancet Regional Health – Western Pacific*. 2022 Oct 1; 27:100567.

Ryunosuke Goto, Roch Nianogo, Yusuke Okubo, Kosuke Inoue. Evaluation of Obesity Trends Among US Adolescents by Socioeconomic Status, 1999-2018. *JAMA Pediatrics*. 2022 June 21;

Yosuke Eriguchi, Xiaoxue Gu, Naoto Aoki, Maiko Nonaka, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Hitoshi Kuwabara, Yukiko Kano, Kiyoto Kasai. A 2-year longitudinal follow-up of quantitative assessment neck tics in Tourette's syndrome. *Plos one.* 2021 Dec 30;16(12):e0261560.

Ryunosuke Goto, Natsumi Matsuda, Maiko Nonaka, Yu Hamamoto, Yosuke Eriguchi, Mayu Fujiwara, Akane Suzuki, Yukari Yokoyama, Yukiko Kano. The Gilles de la Tourette Syndrome-Quality of Life Scale (GTS-QOL): A Validation in Japanese Patients. *Frontiers in psychiatry.* 2022 Jan 3;12:797037.

Ryunosuke Goto, Yoko Watanabe, Ako Yamazaki, Masatoshi Sugita, Satoru Takeda, Masao Nakabayashi, Yasuhide Nakamura. Can digital health technologies exacerbate the health gap? A clustering analysis of mothers' opinions toward digitizing the maternal and child health handbook. *SSM-Population Health.* 2021 Oct;16:100935.

Ryunosuke Goto, Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. *Pediatrics*. 2021 Sep;148(3),e2021050332

Ryunosuke Goto, Ryo Inuzuka, Takahiro Shindo, Yoshiyuki Namai, Yoichiro Oda, Yutaka Harita, Akira Oka. Relationship between post-IVIG IgG levels and clinical outcomes in Kawasaki disease patients: new insight into the mechanism of action of IVIG. *Clin Rheumatol.* 2020 Dec;39: 3747-55.

Seif Nasir*, **Ryunosuke Goto***, Akiko Kitamura, Sahar Alafeef, Ghada Ballout, Majed Hababeh, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba.Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCHHandbook, UNRWA's newly released maternal and child health mobile application: a cross-sectional study. *BMJ Open*. 2020;10:e034885. (*joint first authors)

Ryunosuke Goto, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Marina Nobuyoshi, Maiko Nonaka, Toshiaki Kono, Masaki Kojima, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. The effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress caused by compulsive-like behavior in very young children: a cross-sectional study. *Child Adolesc Psychiatry Ment Health*. 2019 Jun 28;13:28.

Other publications

Ryunosuke Goto, Yoko Watanabe, Yasuhide Nakamura. JAPAN: Digitization of MCH Handbook and the socioeconomic disparity in health. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. Jun 2022.

 $\frac{https://www.jica.go.jp/activities/issues/health/mch_handbook/ku57pq000028koi9-att/technical_brief_41.pdf.$

Ryunosuke Goto, Anthony P. S. Guerrero, Mario Speranza, Daniel Fung, Campbell Paul, Norbert Skokauskas. War is a public health emergency. *The Lancet*. 2022 Apr 2; 399(1302):1302.

Akiko Kitamura, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Seif Nasir, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Akihiro Seita. JORDAN: UNRWA's electric MCH Handbook application for Palestine Refugees. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. August 2017. http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631_02.pdf.

Japanese translation of: Cohn SL. Preoperative Evaluation for Noncardiac Surgery. *Ann Intern Med.* 2016;165:JITC81-JITC96. http://annals.org/data/journals/aim/935916/aitc201612060 japanese.pdf

Conference Presentations

Oral Presentations

Ryunosuke Goto, Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) National Conference and Exhibition (International Conference), Philadelphia, PA, United States (virtual). October, 2021.

Ryunosuke Goto, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. Effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress by compulsive-like behavior in very young children. 24th World Congress of the International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) (International Conference), Singapore. December, 2020.

Ryunosuke Goto, Seif Nasir, Akiko Kitamura, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba. Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCH Handbook, the potential role of m-Health in improving health equity in a refugee setting: A cross-sectional study. **American Public Health Association** (**APHA**) **Annual Meeting (International Conference)**, San Diego, CA, United States. November, 2018.

Invited Presentations

Ryunosuke Goto. What changes can the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook bring to health care? An example from Jordan. 4th annual Maternal and Child Health Handbook Forum, Tokyo, Japan. October 8, 2019. An overview on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and Palestine refugees

Ryunosuke Goto. Social common capital and health: from a global perspective. **Nikkei SDGs Forum**, Tokyo, Japan. May 9, 2019.

A presentation on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and how it contributed to health equity for Palestine refugees

Qualifications

TOEFL iBT 118/120

09/2017

United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE) Step 2 Clinical Skills

Honors and Awards

Donald J. Cohen Fellowship Program for International Scholars in Child and Adolescent Mental Health

12/2020

Awarded to emerging leaders in child and adolescent mental health throughout the world, and is awarded at the International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) Congress

The University of Tokyo Faculty of Medicine Dean's Award 01/2018

Awarded to the top three out of about 120 students in the Class of 2019, based on excellence in clinical rotations

The University of Tokyo Osamu Otsubo Fellowship

01/2018

A scholarship awarded to top students who aspire to receive medical education abroad

The University of Tokyo Go Global Scholarship

Autumn 2017 and Spring 2018

A scholarship awarded to top students to study abroad

Pigeon Foundation Scholarship for Aspiring Pediatricians, Obstetricians, and Gynecologists

04/2017 - 03/2019

A scholarship awarded to top medical students who aim to become pediatricians, obstetricians, or gynecologists

U.S. Clinical Experience

Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, Boston Children's Hospital (clinical clerkship)

05/2018 - 06/2018 (4 weeks)

Pediatric Critical Care Unit, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (observership) 04/2018 - 05/2018 (4 weeks)

Pediatric Surgery, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (clinical clerkship) 03/2018 - 04/2018 (4 weeks)